<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<mes:GenericMetadata xmlns:mes="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v2_1/message" xmlns:gen="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v2_1/metadata/generic" xmlns:com="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v2_1/common">
  <mes:Header>
    <mes:ID>IREF1627607924</mes:ID>
    <mes:Test>True</mes:Test>
    <mes:Prepared>2021-07-30T01:18:44</mes:Prepared>
    <mes:Sender id="open-sdg_sdg-build@1-4-0"/>
    <mes:Structure structureID="MDS1">
      <com:Structure>
        <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.metadatastructure.MetadataStructure=IAEG-SDGs:SDG_MSD(0.3)</URN>
      </com:Structure>
    </mes:Structure>
  </mes:Header>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="13c2cab5-ebb5-48e8-9501-44d057d62bf1">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SE_ADT_ACTS</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>MZ</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Directorate of Planning, Studies and Cooperation </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 4: Guarantee Access to Inclusive, Quality and Equitable Education and, Promote Lifelong Learning Opportunities for All. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 4.4 By 2030, substantially increase the number of young people and adults who have relevant skills, including technical and professional skills, for employment, decent work and entrepreneurship. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 4.4.1 Percentage of young people and adults with skills in information and communication technology (ICT), by type of skill. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Percentage of young people and adults with skills in information and communication technology (ICT), by type of skill. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 10/8/2020 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Science and Technology, Higher Education and Professional Technician (MCTESTP) </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Tomé Lucas Wilson, Innocence Pale </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Head of the Planning and Monitoring Department and statistical technique </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> +258849136315, 847093829/827111410 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <h2> <a href="mailto:tome.wilson@mctestp.gov.mz"> <u> tome.wilson@mctestp.gov.mz </u> </a>, inocencia.phale@mctestp.gov.mz a0f559170]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> <a href="mailto:toluwil@gmail.com"> <u> toluwil@gmail.com </u> </a>, <a href="mailto:inocencia.pale@gmail.com"> innencia.]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Percentage of young people (15 to 24 years old) and adults (aged 15 years and over) who performed certain computer activities in a certain period of time. Computer-related activities to measure ICT skills include: </p>
 <p> • Copy or move a file </p>
 <p> • Use of copy and paste tools to duplicate or move information within the same document; </p>
 <p> • Sending e-mail with file attachments (e.g. photo, video); </p>
 <p> • Use of basic arithmetic formula in a spreadsheet; </p>
 <p> • Connection and installation of new devices (e.g. modem, camera, printer); </p>
 <p> • Find, download, install and configure software; </p>
 <p> • Creation of electronic presentations with presentation software (including text, images, sound, video or graphics); </p>
 <p> • Transferring files between a computer and other devices; </p>
 <p> • Write a computer program using a specialized programming language. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Percentage </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Science and Technology, Higher Education and Professional Technician (MCTESTP), Administrative data. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The data for the determination of this indicator are obtained through administrative surveys carried out by the National Institute of Electronic Government in the scope of the Training of Young People, Women, Officials and State Agents. Data is collected at the provincial digital resource centers and some at the ICT training centers. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> March of each year </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> December each year </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Science and Technology, Higher Education and Professional Technician through the National Institute of Electronic Government. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Science and Technology, Higher Education and Professional Technician through the National Institute of Electronic Government. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The Ministry and delegated organ of Statistics Portugal. </p>
 <p> Produces statistics from the Science and Technology, Higher Education and Professional Technical Sector according to the joint order of December 2002, Bulletin of the Republic no <sup> o </sup> 10, Series, of March 5, 2003. a0679c9a6a6d43]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> This indicator links the use and impact of ICT and helps to measure and track the level of proficiency of users. A high value indicates that a large portion of the reference population has ICT skills. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The data collected to calculate the indicator do not capture information from private training centers that teach courses in the areas of ICT and are not disaggregated by type of skill. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> This indicator is obtained by the ratio between the number of young people and adults who have ICT skills and the total population resident in the country, multiplied by 100%. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The results of this operation are analyzed by the department of studies and statistics and then presented to the technical and advisory councils of the ministry for the purposes of assessment and final validation. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> To produce this indicator, methodological guidelines are used, which are included in the globally available metadata, the difference is in the fact that globally they use the type of specific skills while at the national level they apply all kinds of skills. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> In process the creation of the management system at the level of the national statistical system, however at the level of the ministry there is a department to manage the quality of statistical products: </p>
 <ol>
   <li> Collection and made through administrative acts. </li>
   <li> After collection, the studies and statistics department checks the quality of the entire process. </li>
 </ol>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> To guarantee the quality required in the Statistics production process, the sector uses all correlated administrative information sources, in order to complement, validate and measure the information obtained. Also during the process of analysis and establishment of the data values, the sources of origin of the basic information are questioned whenever there are doubts or anomalous variations in the results obtained. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The instruments for assessing the quality of statistical processes and products at the level of the national statistical system are being developed based on the 19 quality principles established by the united nations statistics commission. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The data for this indicator are available annually and are not broken down by type of skill. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The determination of this indicator differs from the international one in that it relates people with ICT skills and the total population residing in the country and not a specific age group. The other aspect refers to the data source, for this indicator the data source used for the calculation is administrative and not survey. The calculation is not done by type of skill considers all skills. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Annual Balance of Activities of the CTESTP Sector. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
</mes:GenericMetadata>
        