<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<mes:GenericMetadata xmlns:mes="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v2_1/message" xmlns:gen="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v2_1/metadata/generic" xmlns:com="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v2_1/common">
  <mes:Header>
    <mes:ID>IREF1627613272</mes:ID>
    <mes:Test>True</mes:Test>
    <mes:Prepared>2021-07-30T02:47:52</mes:Prepared>
    <mes:Sender id="open-sdg_sdg-build@1-4-0"/>
    <mes:Structure structureID="MDS1">
      <com:Structure>
        <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.metadatastructure.MetadataStructure=IAEG-SDGs:SDG_MSD(0.3)</URN>
      </com:Structure>
    </mes:Structure>
  </mes:Header>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="4a84755f-cf1f-4b34-bf6e-49f290ccc920">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>VC_VAW_NONMARR</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>MZ</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Directorate of Demographic, Vital and Social Statistics </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5. ACHIEVE GENDER EQUALITY AND EMPOWER ALL WOMEN AND GIRLS </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5.2 Eliminate all forms of violence against all women and girls in the public and private spheres, including trafficking and sexual and other exploitation </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5.2.2 Proportion of women and girls aged 15-49 years subjected to sexual violence by people other than intimate partners in the last 12 months </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Proportion of women and girls aged 15-49 years subjected to sexual violence by people other than intimate partners in the last 12 months </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 10/6/2020 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_RELATED_INDICATORS">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Not applicable </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Not applicable </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF STATISTICS </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Teixeira Mandlate, Maria Alfeu and Joao Mangue </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Tecnicos </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> +258 844386629; +258 823032619; +258 827679480 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> www.ine.gov.mz </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> <a href="mailto:Teixeira.mandlate@ine.gov.mz"> Teixeira.mandlate@ine.gov.mz </a>; <a href="mailto:maria.alfeu@ine.gov.mz"> maria.alfeu@ine.gov.mz </a>; <a href="mailto:joao.mangue@ine.gov.mz"> joao.mangue@ine.gov.mz </a> </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> This indicator measures the percentage of women and girls, aged 15 or over (have ever experienced any form of formal or informal union), who have suffered physical, sexual or psychological violence from their current or former intimate partner, in the last 12 months . </p>
 <p> According to the United Nations Declaration on the Elimination of Violence against Women (1993), Violence against Women is “Any act of gender-based violence that results or may result in physical, sexual or psychological harm or suffering to women, including threats of such acts, coercion or arbitrary deprivation of liberty, occurring in public or private life. Violence against women should be understood as covering, but not limited to, the following: Physical, sexual and psychological violence that occurs in the family [...] </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Percentage </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Demographic and Health Survey (IDS) </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The recommended data source for calculating this indicator are household surveys (IOF and IDS) with national representation that constitute the data source. In either case, the child&#39;s height and weight should be measured following the recommended standard measurement techniques (WHO 2008). </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 2021 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 2022 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> INE, MISAU </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> INE, MISAU </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Law 7/96 of 5 July </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Data on the prevalence of violence against women and girls are needed to measure the magnitude of the problem; understand the various forms of violence and its consequences; identify high-risk groups; explore barriers to seek help; and ensure that appropriate responses are provided. This data is the starting point for informing laws, policies and developing effective responses and programs, as needed. They also allow countries to monitor changes over time and evaluate the effectiveness of their interventions. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The availability of comparable data remains a challenge in this area, as many data collection efforts are based on different research methodologies, use different definitions of violence by the partner or spouse, and different forms of violence, different formulation of questions research, and different age groups are often used. The willingness to discuss experiences of violence and the understanding of relevant concepts can also differ according to the cultural context and this can affect the reported prevalence levels. </p>
 <p> Obtaining data on violence against women is an expensive and time-consuming exercise, whether obtained through dedicated independent surveys or modules inserted in other surveys. Demographic and Health Surveys (IDS) are carried out approximately every 5 years, and dedicated surveys, if repeated, are carried out less frequently than that of IDS. Monitoring this indicator on a regular basis can be a challenge if sustainable capacities are not built and financial resources are not available. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Number of women and girls aged 15 or over (who have ever experienced any form of formal or informal union), who have experienced sexual violence by their current or former intimate partner in the past 12 months, divided by the number of women and girls aged 15 years and more (who have ever experienced any form of formal or informal union), multiplied by 100. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The field work had close supervision and quality control by the central and provincial technicians, both from INE, MISAU and ICF International staff. In addition, during the data collection, a strict control was established at the level of each team over the collection process, by detecting errors by the field critics, which allowed for immediate correction still on the ground. At the level of central coordination, the data critics carried out a further review of the base data and the problems encountered were communicated to the respective teams. </p>
 <p> The interactive and batch processing of information through the CSPro program also allowed, at central level, the periodic obtaining of partial results, for analysis of the data collected until a given moment, through the production of tables for monitoring and quality control. The results of these tabulations were reported in feedback to the interviewers, ensuring data quality. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The Demographic and Health Survey (IDS) in Mozambique is part of an international survey program (MEASURE DHS) developed by ICF International through a contract with USAID, with the purpose of supporting governments and private institutions in developing countries in conducting national surveys by sampling, in the areas of population and health. The MEASURE DHS Program aims to: • Support the formulation of policies and the implementation of programs in the areas of population and health; • Increase the international population and health data base for monitoring and evaluation; • Improve the survey methodology by sampling, and • Consolidate, in the survey area, the technical capacity of the executing institution in the country participating in the Program. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> For data collection, the methodology of interviews was applied face to face with households, applying three types of questionnaires: </p>
 <p> • Household Questionnaire </p>
 <p> • Women&#39;s Questionnaire </p>
 <p> • Men&#39;s Questionnaire. </p>
 <p> The questionnaires were based on the model used by the Demographic and Health surveys in their sixth phase. In addition to the main questions of the sixth phase IDS, some modifications were made to the questions and some specific questions were added in order to satisfy and answer the country&#39;s needs. It should be noted that these instruments have been properly pre-tested in urban and rural areas </p>
 <p> The sample design of IDS-2011 comprises a probabilistic, stratified and multi-stage sample, selected from the Data and Cartography of the III General Census of Population and Housing, carried out by INE in 2007. The sample allows to obtain accurate estimates at the level national, urban and rural, regional and provincial. The sample covers only the population residing in households. Households and respective members residing in collective residences, such as hotels, hospitals, military barracks, student homes, etc., and homeless people, which together make up 3.3% of the country&#39;s total population, were excluded from the sample. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The interactive and batch processing of information through the CSPro program also allowed, at central level, the periodic obtaining of partial results, for analysis of the data collected until a given moment, through the production of tables for monitoring and quality control. The results of these tabulations were reported in feedback to the interviewers, ensuring data quality. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The information is made available every 5 years and is disaggregated by age, rural and urban residence area, province, country </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The production of data allows comparability because the procedures that lead to the collection, treatment and dissemination follow the internationally defined recommendations in <strong> <em> Principles and Recommendations for Civil Statistics - UN, (ST / ESA / STAT / SER.M / 19 / Rev. 3 New York, 2014) </em> </strong> </p>
 <p> Estimates of Demographic and Health Surveys are based on standardized methodologies and developed by WHO and UNICEF. </p>
 <p> Comparability is guaranteed since the Demographic and Health Survey (IDS) in Mozambique is part of an international survey program (MEASURE DHS) developed by ICF International through a contract with USAID, with the purpose of supporting governments and private institutions in developing countries to carry out national sample surveys in the areas of population and health. The MEASURE DHS Program aims to: </p>
 <p> • Support the formulation of policies and implementation of programs in the areas of population and health; </p>
 <p> • Increase the international population and health data base for monitoring and evaluation; </p>
 <p> • Improve the survey methodology by sampling, and </p>
 <p> • Consolidate, in the survey area, the technical capacity of the executing institution in the country participating in the Program. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Health (MISAU), <a href="http://www.misau.gov.mz"> www.misau.gov.mz </a>; </p>
 <p> National Statistics Institute (INE), <a href="http://www.misau.gov.mz"> www.misau.gov.mz </a>; </p>
 <p> ICF International (ICFI), <a href="http://www.measuredhs.com"> www.measuredhs.com </a> </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="740cf03b-f925-4303-828c-a094f91ee077">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>IT_MOB_OWN</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>MZ</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Directorate of Demographic, Vital and Social Statistics </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5. ACHIEVE GENDER EQUALITY AND EMPOWER ALL WOMEN AND GIRLS </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5.b Increase the use of basic technologies, in particular information and communication technologies, to promote the empowerment of women </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5.b.1 Percentage of individuals aged 3 and over who have a mobile phone, by sex, area of residence and province </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Percentage of individuals aged 3 and over who have a mobile phone, by sex, area of residence and province </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 10/6/2020 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_RELATED_INDICATORS">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Not applicable </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Not applicable </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF STATISTICS </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Teixeira Mandlate, Maria Alfeu and João Mangue </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Tecnicos </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> +258 844386629; +258 823032619; +258 827679480 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> www.ine.gov.mz </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> <a href="mailto:Teixeira.mandlate@ine.gov.mz"> Teixeira.mandlate@ine.gov.mz </a>; <a href="mailto:maria.alfeu@ine.gov.mz"> maria.alfeu@ine.gov.mz </a>; <a href="mailto:joao.mangue@ine.gov.mz"> joao.mangue@ine.gov.mz </a> </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> This indicator is defined as the "proportion of individuals aged 3 years and over who have a cell phone, by sex, area of residence and province". </p>
 <p> An individual is the holder of a cell phone if he / she has a cell phone device with at least one active SIM card for personal use. Mobile cell phones provided by employers that can be used for personal reasons (to make personal calls, access the Internet, etc.) are included. Individuals who have only active SIM card (s) and not a cell phone device are excluded. Also included are individuals who have a cell phone for personal use that is not registered in their name. It is considered an active SIM card if it is a SIM card used in the last three months. A mobile phone (cell phone) refers to a portable phone through which you subscribe to a public mobile phone service using cellular technology, which provides access to PSTN. This includes analog and digital cellular systems and technologies, such as IMT-2000 (3G) and IMT-Advanced. Postpaid phone users and prepaid accounts are included. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Percentage </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> IV General Population and Housing Census, 2017 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The recommended data source for calculating this indicator is the Censuses and Household Surveys. This indicator is calculated by dividing the total number of people in the scope who have a cell phone by the total number of people in the scope. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 2027 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 2029 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> INE, MTC </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> INE </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Law 7/96 of 5 July </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The possession of the cell phone, in particular, is important for tracking gender equality, as the cell phone is a personal device that, if owned and not just shared, provides women with a certain degree of independence and autonomy, including for purposes professionals. Several studies have highlighted the link between cell phone ownership and empowerment and productivity growth. </p>
 <p> Existing data on the proportion of women who have a cell phone suggests that fewer women than men have a cell phone. This indicator highlights the importance of cell phone ownership to track and improve gender equality, and monitoring will help develop policies aimed at overcoming gender inequality. The collection of this indicator was proposed by the Gender Working Group of the Partnership on ICT Measurement for Development. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Although data on the “proportion of individuals who own a cell phone” currently exists for only very few countries, the ITU is encouraging all countries to collect data on this indicator through national surveys and the indicator is expected to be added to the list of indicators of the Partnership on ICT Measurement for development. The number of countries with official data for this indicator is expected to increase in the near future. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Countries can collect data on this indicator through national household surveys. This indicator is calculated by dividing the total number of people in the scope who have a cell phone by the total number of people in the scope. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The field work had close supervision and quality control by the central and provincial technicians, both from INE Central and from the Provincial Delegations. In addition, during the data collection, a strict control was established at the level of each team over the collection process, by detecting errors by the field critics, which allowed for immediate correction still on the ground. At the level of central coordination, the data critics carried out a further review of the base data and the problems encountered were communicated to the respective teams. </p>
 <p> Interactive and batch processing of information also allowed, at central level, the periodic obtaining of partial results, for analysis of the data collected until a given moment, through the production of tables for monitoring and quality control. The results of these tabulations were reported in feedback to the inquirers, ensuring the quality of the data. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> This is a newly developed ITU indicator that was approved by the 2014 World Telecommunication / ICT Indicators (WTIS) Symposium. The definition and methodology of the indicator were developed under ITU coordination, through its Groups of Experts and after an extensive consultation process with countries. The main source of data are administrative records, household surveys (IOF and FinScope) and the General Population and Housing Census. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> For the collection of data, the methodology of interviews was applied face to face to the households. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The interactive and batch processing of information also allowed, at central level, the periodic obtaining of partial results, for the analysis of the data collected until a given moment, through the production of tables for monitoring and quality control. The results of these tabulations were reported in feedback to the interviewers, ensuring data quality. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Data are available every 5 years and are disaggregated by sex, age, rural and urban residence area, provincial and country </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The definition and methodology of the indicator were developed under the coordination of the ITU, through its Groups of Experts and after an extensive consultation process with countries </p>
 <p> Comparability is guaranteed since the Demographic and Health Survey (IDS) in Mozambique is part of an international survey program (MEASURE DHS) developed by ICF International through a contract with USAID, with the purpose of supporting governments and private institutions in developing countries to carry out national sample surveys in the areas of population and health. The MEASURE DHS Program aims to: </p>
 <p> • Support the formulation of policies and implementation of programs in the areas of population and health; </p>
 <p> • Increase the international population and health data base for monitoring and evaluation; </p>
 <p> • Improve the survey methodology by sampling, and </p>
 <p> • Consolidate, in the survey area, the technical capacity of the executing institution in the country participating in the Program. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Health (MISAU), <a href="http://www.misau.gov.mz"> www.misau.gov.mz </a>; </p>
 <p> National Statistics Institute (INE), <a href="http://www.misau.gov.mz"> www.misau.gov.mz </a>; </p>
 <p> ICF International (ICFI), <a href="http://www.measuredhs.com"> www.measuredhs.com </a> </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="cb41b7a5-3829-461f-9624-b5db27ef2d84">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SG_LGL_GENEQLFP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>MZ</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Planning and Cooperation Directorate </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5. Achieve gender equality and empower all women and girls </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5.1 End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <h1> 5.1.1 Whether or not legal frameworks exist to promote, apply and monitor equality and non-discrimination based on sex </h1>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5.1.1 Legal frameworks to promote, apply and monitor equality and non-discrimination based on sex, whether existing or not. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 10/3/2020 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_RELATED_INDICATORS">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> No indicators related to0679c9a6a6d43z0]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ângelo Tivane and Arnaldo Muthemba </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Head of the Planning Department; Statistics technician </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> +258 828351430; +258 840560048; </p>
 <p> +258 826081976; +258 842268933 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> <a href="mailto:Angelotivane2011@gmail.com"> Angelotivane2011@gmail.com </a>; <a href="mailto:muthembarnaldo@gmail.com" target="_blank"> muthembarnaldo@gmail.com </a> </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> <a href="mailto:Angelotivane2011@gmail.com"> Angelotivane2011@gmail.com </a>; <a href="mailto:muthembarnaldo@gmail.com" target="_blank"> muthembarnaldo@gmail.com </a> </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The indicator measures the government&#39;s efforts to establish legal frameworks that promote, apply and monitor gender equality. </p>
 <p> The indicator is based on an assessment of legal frameworks that promote, apply and monitor gender equality </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Percentage </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Administrative source. Ministry of Justice, Constitutional and Religious Affairs and the Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action surveyed the existing legislation on the matter and updates it annually, answered the questions and proceeds to the calculation according to international procedures. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> March 2020 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> April 2020 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Justice, Constitutional and Religious Affairs and the Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Presidential Decree nº 9/2015, of 13 March, Resolution nº 18/2015, of 10 July; Ministerial Diploma 117/2015, of December 31; </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The indicator is based on the use of the questionnaire composed of 45 “yes / no” answer questions in four areas of law: (i) Comprehensive legal frameworks and public life; (ii) violence against women; (iii) employment and economic benefits; and (iv) marriage and family. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The indicator is reliable, as the data are collected at source at national level and is internationally comparable. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The indicator is based on the assessment of legal frameworks that promote, apply and monitor gender equality using a questionnaire consisting of 45 binary “Yes / No” answer questions in four areas of law, drawn from the international legal and political framework on equality in particular, CEDAW and the Beijing Platform for Action </p>
 <p> The answers to the questions are coded with simple answers "Yes / No", with "1" for "Yes" and "0" for "No". Only for questions 1 and 2, they can be scored as "N / A", in which case they are not included as part of the overall score calculation for area <sup> <a href="#footnote-2" id="footnote-ref-2"> [2] </a> </sup>. </p>
 <p> The scoring methodology is the unweighted average of the questions in each area of the law, calculated as follows: </p>
 <p>. </p>
 <p> Where <sub> i </sub> refers to the right area <strong> i </strong>; m <sub> i </sub> refers to the total number of questions in the area of the law <strong> i </strong>; <sup> <a href="#footnote-3" id="footnote-ref-3"> [3] </a> </sup> q <sub> </sub> 1 + ... + q <sub> mi </sub> refers to the sum of coded questions in the legal and where q i area <sub> </sub> = "1" if the answer is "Yes" eq <sub> i </sub> = ”0” if the answer is “No”. </p>
 <p> The results of the four areas are reported as a percentage panel (A <sub> </sub> 1, A 2 <sub> </sub>, <sub> The </sub> 3, A 4 <sub> </sub>). The score for each area (a number between 0 and 100) therefore represents the percentage of that country&#39;s achievements in that area, with 100 being best practices answered in all questions in the area. The choice to present all four scores in the area without additional aggregation is the result of adopting the stance that high values in one area in one country need not compensate in any way for the country with low values in some other area and that a comprehensive examination The value of these four numbers for each country is potentially more informative than trying to summarize all four numbers in a single index. </p> <div class="footnotes"> <div> <sup class="footnote-number" id="footnote-2"> 2 </sup> <p> For questions 1 and 2, the methodology does not give a positive or negative score to the existence or are subject to the existence of a Therefore, in countries where customary or personal law does not apply, these questions are classified as "N / A" and are not included as part of the overall score calculation for the &#39;comprehensive legal frameworks and public life&#39; area. <a href="#footnote-ref-2"> ↑ </a> </p> </div> <div> <sup class="footnote-number" id="footnote-3"> 3 </sup> a0d0d0n0d0n0d0n0d <a href="#footnote-ref-3"> ↑ </a> </p> </div> </div>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Validation is done by the collective by the national gender direction then by the technical and advisory council </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The method used is in accordance with international measurement standards of this indicator </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The data are analyzed by the Monitoring and Evaluation Division team, by the head of the Planning Department, by the Director of planning and cooperation, by the Technical Council and finally by the Advisory Council of the Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Working with gender focal points contributes to the quality of the answers given to the questions 45 questions that contribute to the calculation of the indicator </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action is organizing the statistical area to work in coordination with the National Statistics Institute (INE) to improve the quality of the entire process, from data collection to data publication. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The data is disaggregated into Four areas of law: (i) comprehensive legal frameworks and public life; (ii) violence against women; (iii) employment and economic benefits; and (iv) marriage and family. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> This indicator is global and can be compared with other countries. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> www.mgcas.mz.co </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="994714d3-070c-443e-b8df-19444c97e234">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SG_LGL_GENEQVAW</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>MZ</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Planning and Cooperation Directorate </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5. Achieve gender equality and empower all women and girls </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5.1 End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <h1> 5.1.1 Whether or not legal frameworks exist to promote, apply and monitor equality and non-discrimination based on sex </h1>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5.1.1 Legal frameworks to promote, apply and monitor equality and non-discrimination based on sex, whether existing or not. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 10/3/2020 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_RELATED_INDICATORS">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> No indicators related to0679c9a6a6d43z0]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ângelo Tivane and Arnaldo Muthemba </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Head of the Planning Department; Statistics technician </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> +258 828351430; +258 840560048; </p>
 <p> +258 826081976; +258 842268933 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> <a href="mailto:Angelotivane2011@gmail.com"> Angelotivane2011@gmail.com </a>; <a href="mailto:muthembarnaldo@gmail.com" target="_blank"> muthembarnaldo@gmail.com </a> </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> <a href="mailto:Angelotivane2011@gmail.com"> Angelotivane2011@gmail.com </a>; <a href="mailto:muthembarnaldo@gmail.com" target="_blank"> muthembarnaldo@gmail.com </a> </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The indicator measures the government&#39;s efforts to establish legal frameworks that promote, apply and monitor gender equality. </p>
 <p> The indicator is based on an assessment of legal frameworks that promote, apply and monitor gender equality </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Percentage </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Administrative source. Ministry of Justice, Constitutional and Religious Affairs and the Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action surveyed the existing legislation on the matter and updates it annually, answered the questions and proceeds to the calculation according to international procedures. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> March 2020 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> April 2020 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Justice, Constitutional and Religious Affairs and the Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Presidential Decree nº 9/2015, of 13 March, Resolution nº 18/2015, of 10 July; Ministerial Diploma 117/2015, of December 31; </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The indicator is based on the use of the questionnaire composed of 45 “yes / no” answer questions in four areas of law: (i) Comprehensive legal frameworks and public life; (ii) violence against women; (iii) employment and economic benefits; and (iv) marriage and family. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The indicator is reliable, as the data are collected at source at national level and is internationally comparable. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The indicator is based on the assessment of legal frameworks that promote, apply and monitor gender equality using a questionnaire consisting of 45 binary “Yes / No” answer questions in four areas of law, drawn from the international legal and political framework on equality in particular, CEDAW and the Beijing Platform for Action </p>
 <p> The answers to the questions are coded with simple answers "Yes / No", with "1" for "Yes" and "0" for "No". Only for questions 1 and 2, they can be scored as "N / A", in which case they are not included as part of the overall score calculation for area <sup> <a href="#footnote-2" id="footnote-ref-2"> [2] </a> </sup>. </p>
 <p> The scoring methodology is the unweighted average of the questions in each area of the law, calculated as follows: </p>
 <p>. </p>
 <p> Where <sub> i </sub> refers to the right area <strong> i </strong>; m <sub> i </sub> refers to the total number of questions in the area of the law <strong> i </strong>; <sup> <a href="#footnote-3" id="footnote-ref-3"> [3] </a> </sup> q <sub> </sub> 1 + ... + q <sub> mi </sub> refers to the sum of coded questions in the legal and where q i area <sub> </sub> = "1" if the answer is "Yes" eq <sub> i </sub> = ”0” if the answer is “No”. </p>
 <p> The results of the four areas are reported as a percentage panel (A <sub> </sub> 1, A 2 <sub> </sub>, <sub> The </sub> 3, A 4 <sub> </sub>). The score for each area (a number between 0 and 100) therefore represents the percentage of that country&#39;s achievements in that area, with 100 being best practices answered in all questions in the area. The choice to present all four scores in the area without additional aggregation is the result of adopting the stance that high values in one area in one country need not compensate in any way for the country with low values in some other area and that a comprehensive examination The value of these four numbers for each country is potentially more informative than trying to summarize all four numbers in a single index. </p> <div class="footnotes"> <div> <sup class="footnote-number" id="footnote-2"> 2 </sup> <p> For questions 1 and 2, the methodology does not give a positive or negative score to the existence or are subject to the existence of a Therefore, in countries where customary or personal law does not apply, these questions are classified as "N / A" and are not included as part of the overall score calculation for the &#39;comprehensive legal frameworks and public life&#39; area. <a href="#footnote-ref-2"> ↑ </a> </p> </div> <div> <sup class="footnote-number" id="footnote-3"> 3 </sup> a0d0d0n0d0n0d0n0d <a href="#footnote-ref-3"> ↑ </a> </p> </div> </div>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Validation is done by the collective by the national gender direction then by the technical and advisory council </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The method used is in accordance with international measurement standards of this indicator </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The data are analyzed by the Monitoring and Evaluation Division team, by the head of the Planning Department, by the Director of planning and cooperation, by the Technical Council and finally by the Advisory Council of the Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Working with gender focal points contributes to the quality of the answers given to the questions 45 questions that contribute to the calculation of the indicator </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action is organizing the statistical area to work in coordination with the National Statistics Institute (INE) to improve the quality of the entire process, from data collection to data publication. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The data is disaggregated into Four areas of law: (i) comprehensive legal frameworks and public life; (ii) violence against women; (iii) employment and economic benefits; and (iv) marriage and family. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> This indicator is global and can be compared with other countries. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> www.mgcas.mz.co </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="b7948ff0-11aa-4008-9af0-b0b7f1b685f2">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SG_LGL_GENEQEMP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>MZ</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Planning and Cooperation Directorate </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5. Achieve gender equality and empower all women and girls </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5.1 End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <h1> 5.1.1 Whether or not legal frameworks exist to promote, apply and monitor equality and non-discrimination based on sex </h1>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5.1.1 Legal frameworks to promote, apply and monitor equality and non-discrimination based on sex, whether existing or not. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 10/3/2020 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_RELATED_INDICATORS">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> No indicators related to0679c9a6a6d43z0]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ângelo Tivane and Arnaldo Muthemba </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Head of the Planning Department; Statistics technician </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> +258 828351430; +258 840560048; </p>
 <p> +258 826081976; +258 842268933 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> <a href="mailto:Angelotivane2011@gmail.com"> Angelotivane2011@gmail.com </a>; <a href="mailto:muthembarnaldo@gmail.com" target="_blank"> muthembarnaldo@gmail.com </a> </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> <a href="mailto:Angelotivane2011@gmail.com"> Angelotivane2011@gmail.com </a>; <a href="mailto:muthembarnaldo@gmail.com" target="_blank"> muthembarnaldo@gmail.com </a> </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The indicator measures the government&#39;s efforts to establish legal frameworks that promote, apply and monitor gender equality. </p>
 <p> The indicator is based on an assessment of legal frameworks that promote, apply and monitor gender equality </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Percentage </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Administrative source. Ministry of Justice, Constitutional and Religious Affairs and the Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action surveyed the existing legislation on the matter and updates it annually, answered the questions and proceeds to the calculation according to international procedures. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> March 2020 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> April 2020 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Justice, Constitutional and Religious Affairs and the Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Presidential Decree nº 9/2015, of 13 March, Resolution nº 18/2015, of 10 July; Ministerial Diploma 117/2015, of December 31; </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The indicator is based on the use of the questionnaire composed of 45 “yes / no” answer questions in four areas of law: (i) Comprehensive legal frameworks and public life; (ii) violence against women; (iii) employment and economic benefits; and (iv) marriage and family. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The indicator is reliable, as the data are collected at source at national level and is internationally comparable. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The indicator is based on the assessment of legal frameworks that promote, apply and monitor gender equality using a questionnaire consisting of 45 binary “Yes / No” answer questions in four areas of law, drawn from the international legal and political framework on equality in particular, CEDAW and the Beijing Platform for Action </p>
 <p> The answers to the questions are coded with simple answers "Yes / No", with "1" for "Yes" and "0" for "No". Only for questions 1 and 2, they can be scored as "N / A", in which case they are not included as part of the overall score calculation for area <sup> <a href="#footnote-2" id="footnote-ref-2"> [2] </a> </sup>. </p>
 <p> The scoring methodology is the unweighted average of the questions in each area of the law, calculated as follows: </p>
 <p>. </p>
 <p> Where <sub> i </sub> refers to the right area <strong> i </strong>; m <sub> i </sub> refers to the total number of questions in the area of the law <strong> i </strong>; <sup> <a href="#footnote-3" id="footnote-ref-3"> [3] </a> </sup> q <sub> </sub> 1 + ... + q <sub> mi </sub> refers to the sum of coded questions in the legal and where q i area <sub> </sub> = "1" if the answer is "Yes" eq <sub> i </sub> = ”0” if the answer is “No”. </p>
 <p> The results of the four areas are reported as a percentage panel (A <sub> </sub> 1, A 2 <sub> </sub>, <sub> The </sub> 3, A 4 <sub> </sub>). The score for each area (a number between 0 and 100) therefore represents the percentage of that country&#39;s achievements in that area, with 100 being best practices answered in all questions in the area. The choice to present all four scores in the area without additional aggregation is the result of adopting the stance that high values in one area in one country need not compensate in any way for the country with low values in some other area and that a comprehensive examination The value of these four numbers for each country is potentially more informative than trying to summarize all four numbers in a single index. </p> <div class="footnotes"> <div> <sup class="footnote-number" id="footnote-2"> 2 </sup> <p> For questions 1 and 2, the methodology does not give a positive or negative score to the existence or are subject to the existence of a Therefore, in countries where customary or personal law does not apply, these questions are classified as "N / A" and are not included as part of the overall score calculation for the &#39;comprehensive legal frameworks and public life&#39; area. <a href="#footnote-ref-2"> ↑ </a> </p> </div> <div> <sup class="footnote-number" id="footnote-3"> 3 </sup> a0d0d0n0d0n0d0n0d <a href="#footnote-ref-3"> ↑ </a> </p> </div> </div>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Validation is done by the collective by the national gender direction then by the technical and advisory council </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The method used is in accordance with international measurement standards of this indicator </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The data are analyzed by the Monitoring and Evaluation Division team, by the head of the Planning Department, by the Director of planning and cooperation, by the Technical Council and finally by the Advisory Council of the Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Working with gender focal points contributes to the quality of the answers given to the questions 45 questions that contribute to the calculation of the indicator </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action is organizing the statistical area to work in coordination with the National Statistics Institute (INE) to improve the quality of the entire process, from data collection to data publication. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The data is disaggregated into Four areas of law: (i) comprehensive legal frameworks and public life; (ii) violence against women; (iii) employment and economic benefits; and (iv) marriage and family. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> This indicator is global and can be compared with other countries. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> www.mgcas.mz.co </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="c311c1ca-b21e-4be0-bce3-655d20faa50a">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SG_LGL_GENEQMAR</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>MZ</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Planning and Cooperation Directorate </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5. Achieve gender equality and empower all women and girls </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5.1 End all forms of discrimination against all women and girls everywhere </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <h1> 5.1.1 Whether or not legal frameworks exist to promote, apply and monitor equality and non-discrimination based on sex </h1>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5.1.1 Legal frameworks to promote, apply and monitor equality and non-discrimination based on sex, whether existing or not. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 10/3/2020 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_RELATED_INDICATORS">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> No indicators related to0679c9a6a6d43z0]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ângelo Tivane and Arnaldo Muthemba </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Head of the Planning Department; Statistics technician </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> +258 828351430; +258 840560048; </p>
 <p> +258 826081976; +258 842268933 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> <a href="mailto:Angelotivane2011@gmail.com"> Angelotivane2011@gmail.com </a>; <a href="mailto:muthembarnaldo@gmail.com" target="_blank"> muthembarnaldo@gmail.com </a> </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> <a href="mailto:Angelotivane2011@gmail.com"> Angelotivane2011@gmail.com </a>; <a href="mailto:muthembarnaldo@gmail.com" target="_blank"> muthembarnaldo@gmail.com </a> </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The indicator measures the government&#39;s efforts to establish legal frameworks that promote, apply and monitor gender equality. </p>
 <p> The indicator is based on an assessment of legal frameworks that promote, apply and monitor gender equality </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Percentage </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Administrative source. Ministry of Justice, Constitutional and Religious Affairs and the Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action surveyed the existing legislation on the matter and updates it annually, answered the questions and proceeds to the calculation according to international procedures. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> March 2020 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> April 2020 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Justice, Constitutional and Religious Affairs and the Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Presidential Decree nº 9/2015, of 13 March, Resolution nº 18/2015, of 10 July; Ministerial Diploma 117/2015, of December 31; </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The indicator is based on the use of the questionnaire composed of 45 “yes / no” answer questions in four areas of law: (i) Comprehensive legal frameworks and public life; (ii) violence against women; (iii) employment and economic benefits; and (iv) marriage and family. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The indicator is reliable, as the data are collected at source at national level and is internationally comparable. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The indicator is based on the assessment of legal frameworks that promote, apply and monitor gender equality using a questionnaire consisting of 45 binary “Yes / No” answer questions in four areas of law, drawn from the international legal and political framework on equality in particular, CEDAW and the Beijing Platform for Action </p>
 <p> The answers to the questions are coded with simple answers "Yes / No", with "1" for "Yes" and "0" for "No". Only for questions 1 and 2, they can be scored as "N / A", in which case they are not included as part of the overall score calculation for area <sup> <a href="#footnote-2" id="footnote-ref-2"> [2] </a> </sup>. </p>
 <p> The scoring methodology is the unweighted average of the questions in each area of the law, calculated as follows: </p>
 <p>. </p>
 <p> Where <sub> i </sub> refers to the right area <strong> i </strong>; m <sub> i </sub> refers to the total number of questions in the area of the law <strong> i </strong>; <sup> <a href="#footnote-3" id="footnote-ref-3"> [3] </a> </sup> q <sub> </sub> 1 + ... + q <sub> mi </sub> refers to the sum of coded questions in the legal and where q i area <sub> </sub> = "1" if the answer is "Yes" eq <sub> i </sub> = ”0” if the answer is “No”. </p>
 <p> The results of the four areas are reported as a percentage panel (A <sub> </sub> 1, A 2 <sub> </sub>, <sub> The </sub> 3, A 4 <sub> </sub>). The score for each area (a number between 0 and 100) therefore represents the percentage of that country&#39;s achievements in that area, with 100 being best practices answered in all questions in the area. The choice to present all four scores in the area without additional aggregation is the result of adopting the stance that high values in one area in one country need not compensate in any way for the country with low values in some other area and that a comprehensive examination The value of these four numbers for each country is potentially more informative than trying to summarize all four numbers in a single index. </p> <div class="footnotes"> <div> <sup class="footnote-number" id="footnote-2"> 2 </sup> <p> For questions 1 and 2, the methodology does not give a positive or negative score to the existence or are subject to the existence of a Therefore, in countries where customary or personal law does not apply, these questions are classified as "N / A" and are not included as part of the overall score calculation for the &#39;comprehensive legal frameworks and public life&#39; area. <a href="#footnote-ref-2"> ↑ </a> </p> </div> <div> <sup class="footnote-number" id="footnote-3"> 3 </sup> a0d0d0n0d0n0d0n0d <a href="#footnote-ref-3"> ↑ </a> </p> </div> </div>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Validation is done by the collective by the national gender direction then by the technical and advisory council </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The method used is in accordance with international measurement standards of this indicator </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The data are analyzed by the Monitoring and Evaluation Division team, by the head of the Planning Department, by the Director of planning and cooperation, by the Technical Council and finally by the Advisory Council of the Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Working with gender focal points contributes to the quality of the answers given to the questions 45 questions that contribute to the calculation of the indicator </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The Ministry of Gender, Children and Social Action is organizing the statistical area to work in coordination with the National Statistics Institute (INE) to improve the quality of the entire process, from data collection to data publication. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The data is disaggregated into Four areas of law: (i) comprehensive legal frameworks and public life; (ii) violence against women; (iii) employment and economic benefits; and (iv) marriage and family. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> This indicator is global and can be compared with other countries. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> www.mgcas.mz.co </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="57e8c35c-b320-4b8f-a4bc-0f756a8b5835">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_FPL_INFM</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>MZ</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Directorate of Demographic, Vital and Social Statistics </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5 ACHIEVE GENDER EQUALITY AND EMPOWER ALL WOMEN AND GIRLS </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5.6 Ensuring universal access to sexual and reproductive health and reproductive rights, as agreed and in accordance with the Program of Action of the International Conference on Population and Development and the Beijing Platform for Action and the documents resulting from its review conferences </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5.6.1 Percentage of women aged 15 to 49 who make their own informed decisions about sexual relations, contraceptive use and reproductive health care </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Percentage of women aged 15 to 49 who make their own informed decisions about sexual intercourse, contraceptive use and reproductive health care </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 10/23/2020 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_RELATED_INDICATORS">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Not applicable </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Not applicable </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF STATISTICS </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Teixeira Mandlate, Maria Alfeu and Joao Mangue </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Tecnicos </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> +258 844386629; +258 823032619; +258 827679480 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> www.ine.gov.mz </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> <a href="mailto:Teixeira.mandlate@ine.gov.mz"> Teixeira.mandlate@ine.gov.mz </a>; <a href="mailto:maria.alfeu@ine.gov.mz"> maria.alfeu@ine.gov.mz </a>; <a href="mailto:joao.mangue@ine.gov.mz"> joao.mangue@ine.gov.mz </a> </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Proportion of women aged 15 to 49 (married or in union) who make their own decision in the three selected areas, that is, they can say yes or no to sexual intercourse with their husband or partner </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Percentage </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Statistics Portugal, Demographic and health survey (IDS) </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The recommended data sources for calculating this indicator are nationally representative household surveys (IDS) that constitute the data source. In either case, the child&#39;s height and weight should be measured following the recommended standard measurement techniques (WHO 2008). </p>
 <p> The questionnaire for the collection of data from the Demographic and Health Survey was designed and subsequently tested in the field during the training of the interviewers. </p>
 <p> For data collection, the methodology of interviews was applied face to face to the households, applying three types of questionnaires: </p>
 <p> • Household Questionnaire </p>
 <p> • Women&#39;s Questionnaire </p>
 <p> • Men&#39;s Questionnaire. </p>
 <p> The Sample Design </p>
 <p> The Demographic and Health Survey comprises a probabilistic, stratified and multi-stage sample, selected from the Data and Cartography of the III General Census of Population and Housing, carried out by INE in 2007. </p>
 <p> The data collection lasted for five months starting in June 2011, ending in November 2011. </p>
 <p> Response rate </p>
 <p> Of the 13.964 households interviewed in the survey, a total of 13.871 eligible women were identified. Interviews were conducted with 13,718 of these women, which resulted in a response rate of 99%. Introduction • 13 In one third of the IDS household sample, interviews were also conducted with all eligible men found. Thus, of the 4,130 eligible men identified in the subsample of households selected for the men survey, 4,027 were successfully interviewed, giving a response rate of 98% </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 2021 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 2022 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> INE, MISAU </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> INE, MISAU </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Law 7/96 of 5 July </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The autonomy of women and girls in making decisions about consensual sexual relations, the use of contraceptives and access to sexual and reproductive health services is essential for their empowerment and the full exercise of their reproductive rights. The woman&#39;s ability to say "no" to her husband / partner, if she does not want to have sex, is well aligned with the concept of women&#39;s sexual autonomy and empowerment. </p>
 <p> Women who make their own decision regarding seeking medical care are considered to be able to exercise their reproductive rights </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Women who make their own decision to seek medical care are considered to be able to exercise their reproductive rights. </p>
 <p> A key limitation is that the current estimates of the indicator are based on women currently married or in union at the age of reproduction (15 to 49 years) who are using any type of contraception. In the current Demographic and Health Survey (IDS), the question about decision making on contraceptive use is asked only of women who currently use contraceptive methods. As questions about decision-making about sexual relations and health care are restricted to women (15 to 49) currently married or in union, the denominator of Indicator 5.6.1 is women aged 15 to 49, currently married or in union and currently using contraception. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Numerator: Number of women aged 15 to 49 married or in union </p>
 <p> Denominator: Total number of women between 15 and 49 years of age, married or in union </p>
 <p> Proportion = (Numerator / Denominator) * 100 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The field work had close supervision and quality control by the central and provincial technicians, both from INE, MISAU and ICF International staff. In addition, during the data collection, a strict control was established at the level of each team over the collection process, by detecting errors by the field critics, which allowed for immediate correction still on the ground. At the level of central coordination, the data critics carried out a further review of the base data and the problems encountered were communicated to the respective teams. </p>
 <p> The interactive and batch processing of information through the CSPro program also allowed, at central level, the periodic obtaining of partial results, for analysis of the data collected until a given moment, through the production of tables for monitoring and quality control. The results of these tabulations were reported in feedback to the interviewers, ensuring data quality. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The Demographic and Health Survey (IDS) in Mozambique is part of an international survey program (MEASURE DHS) developed by ICF International through a contract with USAID, with the purpose of supporting governments and private institutions in developing countries in conducting national surveys by sampling, in the areas of population and health. The MEASURE DHS Program aims to: </p>
 <p> • Support the formulation of policies and implementation of programs in the areas of population and health; </p>
 <p> • Increase the international population and health data base for monitoring and evaluation; </p>
 <p> • Improve the survey methodology by sampling, and </p>
 <p> • Consolidate, in the survey area, the technical capacity of the executing institution in the country participating in the Program. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Quality Management Instrument still to be approved </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The interactive and batch processing of information through the CSPro program also allowed, at central level, the periodic obtaining of partial results, for analysis of the data collected until a given moment, through the production of tables for monitoring and quality control. The results of these tabulations were reported in feedback to the interviewers, ensuring data quality. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Quality Assessment Instrument still to be approved </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Data are available every 5 years and can be disaggregated by specific age group, rural and urban area of residence, province, education level, employment and wealth quintile </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Estimates of Demographic and Health Surveys are based on standardized methodologies and developed by WHO and UNICEF. </p>
 <p> Comparability is guaranteed since the Demographic and Health Survey (IDS) in Mozambique is part of an international survey program (MEASURE DHS) developed by ICF International through a contract with USAID, with the purpose of supporting governments and private institutions in developing countries to carry out national sample surveys in the areas of population and health. The MEASURE DHS Program aims to: </p>
 <p> • Support the formulation of policies and implementation of programs in the areas of population and health; </p>
 <p> • Increase the international population and health data base for monitoring and evaluation; </p>
 <p> • Improve the survey methodology by sampling, and </p>
 <p> • Consolidate, in the survey area, the technical capacity of the executing institution in the country participating in the Program. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Health (MISAU), <a href="http://www.misau.gov.mz"> www.misau.gov.mz </a>; </p>
 <p> National Statistics Institute (INE), <a href="http://www.misau.gov.mz"> www.misau.gov.mz </a>; </p>
 <p> ICF International (ICFI), <a href="http://www.measuredhs.com"> www.measuredhs.com </a> </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="a2b40e0e-3256-4e87-851f-dae3dcd31fce">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_FPL_INFMSR</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>MZ</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Directorate of Demographic, Vital and Social Statistics </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5 ACHIEVE GENDER EQUALITY AND EMPOWER ALL WOMEN AND GIRLS </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5.6 Ensuring universal access to sexual and reproductive health and reproductive rights, as agreed and in accordance with the Program of Action of the International Conference on Population and Development and the Beijing Platform for Action and the documents resulting from its review conferences </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5.6.1 Percentage of women aged 15 to 49 who make their own informed decisions about sexual relations, contraceptive use and reproductive health care </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Percentage of women aged 15 to 49 who make their own informed decisions about sexual intercourse, contraceptive use and reproductive health care </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 10/23/2020 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_RELATED_INDICATORS">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Not applicable </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Not applicable </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF STATISTICS </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Teixeira Mandlate, Maria Alfeu and Joao Mangue </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Tecnicos </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> +258 844386629; +258 823032619; +258 827679480 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> www.ine.gov.mz </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> <a href="mailto:Teixeira.mandlate@ine.gov.mz"> Teixeira.mandlate@ine.gov.mz </a>; <a href="mailto:maria.alfeu@ine.gov.mz"> maria.alfeu@ine.gov.mz </a>; <a href="mailto:joao.mangue@ine.gov.mz"> joao.mangue@ine.gov.mz </a> </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Proportion of women aged 15 to 49 (married or in union) who make their own decision in the three selected areas, that is, they can say yes or no to sexual intercourse with their husband or partner </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Percentage </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Statistics Portugal, Demographic and health survey (IDS) </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The recommended data sources for calculating this indicator are nationally representative household surveys (IDS) that constitute the data source. In either case, the child&#39;s height and weight should be measured following the recommended standard measurement techniques (WHO 2008). </p>
 <p> The questionnaire for the collection of data from the Demographic and Health Survey was designed and subsequently tested in the field during the training of the interviewers. </p>
 <p> For data collection, the methodology of interviews was applied face to face to the households, applying three types of questionnaires: </p>
 <p> • Household Questionnaire </p>
 <p> • Women&#39;s Questionnaire </p>
 <p> • Men&#39;s Questionnaire. </p>
 <p> The Sample Design </p>
 <p> The Demographic and Health Survey comprises a probabilistic, stratified and multi-stage sample, selected from the Data and Cartography of the III General Census of Population and Housing, carried out by INE in 2007. </p>
 <p> The data collection lasted for five months starting in June 2011, ending in November 2011. </p>
 <p> Response rate </p>
 <p> Of the 13.964 households interviewed in the survey, a total of 13.871 eligible women were identified. Interviews were conducted with 13,718 of these women, which resulted in a response rate of 99%. Introduction • 13 In one third of the IDS household sample, interviews were also conducted with all eligible men found. Thus, of the 4,130 eligible men identified in the subsample of households selected for the men survey, 4,027 were successfully interviewed, giving a response rate of 98% </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 2021 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 2022 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> INE, MISAU </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> INE, MISAU </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Law 7/96 of 5 July </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The autonomy of women and girls in making decisions about consensual sexual relations, the use of contraceptives and access to sexual and reproductive health services is essential for their empowerment and the full exercise of their reproductive rights. The woman&#39;s ability to say "no" to her husband / partner, if she does not want to have sex, is well aligned with the concept of women&#39;s sexual autonomy and empowerment. </p>
 <p> Women who make their own decision regarding seeking medical care are considered to be able to exercise their reproductive rights </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Women who make their own decision to seek medical care are considered to be able to exercise their reproductive rights. </p>
 <p> A key limitation is that the current estimates of the indicator are based on women currently married or in union at the age of reproduction (15 to 49 years) who are using any type of contraception. In the current Demographic and Health Survey (IDS), the question about decision making on contraceptive use is asked only of women who currently use contraceptive methods. As questions about decision-making about sexual relations and health care are restricted to women (15 to 49) currently married or in union, the denominator of Indicator 5.6.1 is women aged 15 to 49, currently married or in union and currently using contraception. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Numerator: Number of women aged 15 to 49 married or in union </p>
 <p> Denominator: Total number of women between 15 and 49 years of age, married or in union </p>
 <p> Proportion = (Numerator / Denominator) * 100 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The field work had close supervision and quality control by the central and provincial technicians, both from INE, MISAU and ICF International staff. In addition, during the data collection, a strict control was established at the level of each team over the collection process, by detecting errors by the field critics, which allowed for immediate correction still on the ground. At the level of central coordination, the data critics carried out a further review of the base data and the problems encountered were communicated to the respective teams. </p>
 <p> The interactive and batch processing of information through the CSPro program also allowed, at central level, the periodic obtaining of partial results, for analysis of the data collected until a given moment, through the production of tables for monitoring and quality control. The results of these tabulations were reported in feedback to the interviewers, ensuring data quality. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The Demographic and Health Survey (IDS) in Mozambique is part of an international survey program (MEASURE DHS) developed by ICF International through a contract with USAID, with the purpose of supporting governments and private institutions in developing countries in conducting national surveys by sampling, in the areas of population and health. The MEASURE DHS Program aims to: </p>
 <p> • Support the formulation of policies and implementation of programs in the areas of population and health; </p>
 <p> • Increase the international population and health data base for monitoring and evaluation; </p>
 <p> • Improve the survey methodology by sampling, and </p>
 <p> • Consolidate, in the survey area, the technical capacity of the executing institution in the country participating in the Program. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Quality Management Instrument still to be approved </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The interactive and batch processing of information through the CSPro program also allowed, at central level, the periodic obtaining of partial results, for analysis of the data collected until a given moment, through the production of tables for monitoring and quality control. The results of these tabulations were reported in feedback to the interviewers, ensuring data quality. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Quality Assessment Instrument still to be approved </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Data are available every 5 years and can be disaggregated by specific age group, rural and urban area of residence, province, education level, employment and wealth quintile </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Estimates of Demographic and Health Surveys are based on standardized methodologies and developed by WHO and UNICEF. </p>
 <p> Comparability is guaranteed since the Demographic and Health Survey (IDS) in Mozambique is part of an international survey program (MEASURE DHS) developed by ICF International through a contract with USAID, with the purpose of supporting governments and private institutions in developing countries to carry out national sample surveys in the areas of population and health. The MEASURE DHS Program aims to: </p>
 <p> • Support the formulation of policies and implementation of programs in the areas of population and health; </p>
 <p> • Increase the international population and health data base for monitoring and evaluation; </p>
 <p> • Improve the survey methodology by sampling, and </p>
 <p> • Consolidate, in the survey area, the technical capacity of the executing institution in the country participating in the Program. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Health (MISAU), <a href="http://www.misau.gov.mz"> www.misau.gov.mz </a>; </p>
 <p> National Statistics Institute (INE), <a href="http://www.misau.gov.mz"> www.misau.gov.mz </a>; </p>
 <p> ICF International (ICFI), <a href="http://www.measuredhs.com"> www.measuredhs.com </a> </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="9a0afd3d-81fc-4073-b7c3-4f5282febd9b">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_FPL_INFMCU</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>MZ</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Directorate of Demographic, Vital and Social Statistics </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5 ACHIEVE GENDER EQUALITY AND EMPOWER ALL WOMEN AND GIRLS </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5.6 Ensuring universal access to sexual and reproductive health and reproductive rights, as agreed and in accordance with the Program of Action of the International Conference on Population and Development and the Beijing Platform for Action and the documents resulting from its review conferences </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5.6.1 Percentage of women aged 15 to 49 who make their own informed decisions about sexual relations, contraceptive use and reproductive health care </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Percentage of women aged 15 to 49 who make their own informed decisions about sexual intercourse, contraceptive use and reproductive health care </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 10/23/2020 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_RELATED_INDICATORS">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Not applicable </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Not applicable </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF STATISTICS </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Teixeira Mandlate, Maria Alfeu and Joao Mangue </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Tecnicos </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> +258 844386629; +258 823032619; +258 827679480 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> www.ine.gov.mz </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> <a href="mailto:Teixeira.mandlate@ine.gov.mz"> Teixeira.mandlate@ine.gov.mz </a>; <a href="mailto:maria.alfeu@ine.gov.mz"> maria.alfeu@ine.gov.mz </a>; <a href="mailto:joao.mangue@ine.gov.mz"> joao.mangue@ine.gov.mz </a> </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Proportion of women aged 15 to 49 (married or in union) who make their own decision in the three selected areas, that is, they can say yes or no to sexual intercourse with their husband or partner </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Percentage </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Statistics Portugal, Demographic and health survey (IDS) </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The recommended data sources for calculating this indicator are nationally representative household surveys (IDS) that constitute the data source. In either case, the child&#39;s height and weight should be measured following the recommended standard measurement techniques (WHO 2008). </p>
 <p> The questionnaire for the collection of data from the Demographic and Health Survey was designed and subsequently tested in the field during the training of the interviewers. </p>
 <p> For data collection, the methodology of interviews was applied face to face to the households, applying three types of questionnaires: </p>
 <p> • Household Questionnaire </p>
 <p> • Women&#39;s Questionnaire </p>
 <p> • Men&#39;s Questionnaire. </p>
 <p> The Sample Design </p>
 <p> The Demographic and Health Survey comprises a probabilistic, stratified and multi-stage sample, selected from the Data and Cartography of the III General Census of Population and Housing, carried out by INE in 2007. </p>
 <p> The data collection lasted for five months starting in June 2011, ending in November 2011. </p>
 <p> Response rate </p>
 <p> Of the 13.964 households interviewed in the survey, a total of 13.871 eligible women were identified. Interviews were conducted with 13,718 of these women, which resulted in a response rate of 99%. Introduction • 13 In one third of the IDS household sample, interviews were also conducted with all eligible men found. Thus, of the 4,130 eligible men identified in the subsample of households selected for the men survey, 4,027 were successfully interviewed, giving a response rate of 98% </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 2021 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 2022 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> INE, MISAU </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> INE, MISAU </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Law 7/96 of 5 July </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The autonomy of women and girls in making decisions about consensual sexual relations, the use of contraceptives and access to sexual and reproductive health services is essential for their empowerment and the full exercise of their reproductive rights. The woman&#39;s ability to say "no" to her husband / partner, if she does not want to have sex, is well aligned with the concept of women&#39;s sexual autonomy and empowerment. </p>
 <p> Women who make their own decision regarding seeking medical care are considered to be able to exercise their reproductive rights </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Women who make their own decision to seek medical care are considered to be able to exercise their reproductive rights. </p>
 <p> A key limitation is that the current estimates of the indicator are based on women currently married or in union at the age of reproduction (15 to 49 years) who are using any type of contraception. In the current Demographic and Health Survey (IDS), the question about decision making on contraceptive use is asked only of women who currently use contraceptive methods. As questions about decision-making about sexual relations and health care are restricted to women (15 to 49) currently married or in union, the denominator of Indicator 5.6.1 is women aged 15 to 49, currently married or in union and currently using contraception. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Numerator: Number of women aged 15 to 49 married or in union </p>
 <p> Denominator: Total number of women between 15 and 49 years of age, married or in union </p>
 <p> Proportion = (Numerator / Denominator) * 100 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The field work had close supervision and quality control by the central and provincial technicians, both from INE, MISAU and ICF International staff. In addition, during the data collection, a strict control was established at the level of each team over the collection process, by detecting errors by the field critics, which allowed for immediate correction still on the ground. At the level of central coordination, the data critics carried out a further review of the base data and the problems encountered were communicated to the respective teams. </p>
 <p> The interactive and batch processing of information through the CSPro program also allowed, at central level, the periodic obtaining of partial results, for analysis of the data collected until a given moment, through the production of tables for monitoring and quality control. The results of these tabulations were reported in feedback to the interviewers, ensuring data quality. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The Demographic and Health Survey (IDS) in Mozambique is part of an international survey program (MEASURE DHS) developed by ICF International through a contract with USAID, with the purpose of supporting governments and private institutions in developing countries in conducting national surveys by sampling, in the areas of population and health. The MEASURE DHS Program aims to: </p>
 <p> • Support the formulation of policies and implementation of programs in the areas of population and health; </p>
 <p> • Increase the international population and health data base for monitoring and evaluation; </p>
 <p> • Improve the survey methodology by sampling, and </p>
 <p> • Consolidate, in the survey area, the technical capacity of the executing institution in the country participating in the Program. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Quality Management Instrument still to be approved </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The interactive and batch processing of information through the CSPro program also allowed, at central level, the periodic obtaining of partial results, for analysis of the data collected until a given moment, through the production of tables for monitoring and quality control. The results of these tabulations were reported in feedback to the interviewers, ensuring data quality. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Quality Assessment Instrument still to be approved </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Data are available every 5 years and can be disaggregated by specific age group, rural and urban area of residence, province, education level, employment and wealth quintile </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Estimates of Demographic and Health Surveys are based on standardized methodologies and developed by WHO and UNICEF. </p>
 <p> Comparability is guaranteed since the Demographic and Health Survey (IDS) in Mozambique is part of an international survey program (MEASURE DHS) developed by ICF International through a contract with USAID, with the purpose of supporting governments and private institutions in developing countries to carry out national sample surveys in the areas of population and health. The MEASURE DHS Program aims to: </p>
 <p> • Support the formulation of policies and implementation of programs in the areas of population and health; </p>
 <p> • Increase the international population and health data base for monitoring and evaluation; </p>
 <p> • Improve the survey methodology by sampling, and </p>
 <p> • Consolidate, in the survey area, the technical capacity of the executing institution in the country participating in the Program. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Health (MISAU), <a href="http://www.misau.gov.mz"> www.misau.gov.mz </a>; </p>
 <p> National Statistics Institute (INE), <a href="http://www.misau.gov.mz"> www.misau.gov.mz </a>; </p>
 <p> ICF International (ICFI), <a href="http://www.measuredhs.com"> www.measuredhs.com </a> </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="75ca42e8-d2e0-4020-bd92-138f5abadf10">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_FPL_INFMRH</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>MZ</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Directorate of Demographic, Vital and Social Statistics </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5 ACHIEVE GENDER EQUALITY AND EMPOWER ALL WOMEN AND GIRLS </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5.6 Ensuring universal access to sexual and reproductive health and reproductive rights, as agreed and in accordance with the Program of Action of the International Conference on Population and Development and the Beijing Platform for Action and the documents resulting from its review conferences </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 5.6.1 Percentage of women aged 15 to 49 who make their own informed decisions about sexual relations, contraceptive use and reproductive health care </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Percentage of women aged 15 to 49 who make their own informed decisions about sexual intercourse, contraceptive use and reproductive health care </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 10/23/2020 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_RELATED_INDICATORS">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Not applicable </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Not applicable </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF STATISTICS </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Teixeira Mandlate, Maria Alfeu and Joao Mangue </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Tecnicos </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> +258 844386629; +258 823032619; +258 827679480 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> www.ine.gov.mz </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> <a href="mailto:Teixeira.mandlate@ine.gov.mz"> Teixeira.mandlate@ine.gov.mz </a>; <a href="mailto:maria.alfeu@ine.gov.mz"> maria.alfeu@ine.gov.mz </a>; <a href="mailto:joao.mangue@ine.gov.mz"> joao.mangue@ine.gov.mz </a> </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Proportion of women aged 15 to 49 (married or in union) who make their own decision in the three selected areas, that is, they can say yes or no to sexual intercourse with their husband or partner </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Percentage </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Statistics Portugal, Demographic and health survey (IDS) </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The recommended data sources for calculating this indicator are nationally representative household surveys (IDS) that constitute the data source. In either case, the child&#39;s height and weight should be measured following the recommended standard measurement techniques (WHO 2008). </p>
 <p> The questionnaire for the collection of data from the Demographic and Health Survey was designed and subsequently tested in the field during the training of the interviewers. </p>
 <p> For data collection, the methodology of interviews was applied face to face to the households, applying three types of questionnaires: </p>
 <p> • Household Questionnaire </p>
 <p> • Women&#39;s Questionnaire </p>
 <p> • Men&#39;s Questionnaire. </p>
 <p> The Sample Design </p>
 <p> The Demographic and Health Survey comprises a probabilistic, stratified and multi-stage sample, selected from the Data and Cartography of the III General Census of Population and Housing, carried out by INE in 2007. </p>
 <p> The data collection lasted for five months starting in June 2011, ending in November 2011. </p>
 <p> Response rate </p>
 <p> Of the 13.964 households interviewed in the survey, a total of 13.871 eligible women were identified. Interviews were conducted with 13,718 of these women, which resulted in a response rate of 99%. Introduction • 13 In one third of the IDS household sample, interviews were also conducted with all eligible men found. Thus, of the 4,130 eligible men identified in the subsample of households selected for the men survey, 4,027 were successfully interviewed, giving a response rate of 98% </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 2021 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> 2022 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> INE, MISAU </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> INE, MISAU </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Law 7/96 of 5 July </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The autonomy of women and girls in making decisions about consensual sexual relations, the use of contraceptives and access to sexual and reproductive health services is essential for their empowerment and the full exercise of their reproductive rights. The woman&#39;s ability to say "no" to her husband / partner, if she does not want to have sex, is well aligned with the concept of women&#39;s sexual autonomy and empowerment. </p>
 <p> Women who make their own decision regarding seeking medical care are considered to be able to exercise their reproductive rights </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Women who make their own decision to seek medical care are considered to be able to exercise their reproductive rights. </p>
 <p> A key limitation is that the current estimates of the indicator are based on women currently married or in union at the age of reproduction (15 to 49 years) who are using any type of contraception. In the current Demographic and Health Survey (IDS), the question about decision making on contraceptive use is asked only of women who currently use contraceptive methods. As questions about decision-making about sexual relations and health care are restricted to women (15 to 49) currently married or in union, the denominator of Indicator 5.6.1 is women aged 15 to 49, currently married or in union and currently using contraception. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Numerator: Number of women aged 15 to 49 married or in union </p>
 <p> Denominator: Total number of women between 15 and 49 years of age, married or in union </p>
 <p> Proportion = (Numerator / Denominator) * 100 </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The field work had close supervision and quality control by the central and provincial technicians, both from INE, MISAU and ICF International staff. In addition, during the data collection, a strict control was established at the level of each team over the collection process, by detecting errors by the field critics, which allowed for immediate correction still on the ground. At the level of central coordination, the data critics carried out a further review of the base data and the problems encountered were communicated to the respective teams. </p>
 <p> The interactive and batch processing of information through the CSPro program also allowed, at central level, the periodic obtaining of partial results, for analysis of the data collected until a given moment, through the production of tables for monitoring and quality control. The results of these tabulations were reported in feedback to the interviewers, ensuring data quality. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The Demographic and Health Survey (IDS) in Mozambique is part of an international survey program (MEASURE DHS) developed by ICF International through a contract with USAID, with the purpose of supporting governments and private institutions in developing countries in conducting national surveys by sampling, in the areas of population and health. The MEASURE DHS Program aims to: </p>
 <p> • Support the formulation of policies and implementation of programs in the areas of population and health; </p>
 <p> • Increase the international population and health data base for monitoring and evaluation; </p>
 <p> • Improve the survey methodology by sampling, and </p>
 <p> • Consolidate, in the survey area, the technical capacity of the executing institution in the country participating in the Program. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Quality Management Instrument still to be approved </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> The interactive and batch processing of information through the CSPro program also allowed, at central level, the periodic obtaining of partial results, for analysis of the data collected until a given moment, through the production of tables for monitoring and quality control. The results of these tabulations were reported in feedback to the interviewers, ensuring data quality. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Quality Assessment Instrument still to be approved </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Data are available every 5 years and can be disaggregated by specific age group, rural and urban area of residence, province, education level, employment and wealth quintile </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Estimates of Demographic and Health Surveys are based on standardized methodologies and developed by WHO and UNICEF. </p>
 <p> Comparability is guaranteed since the Demographic and Health Survey (IDS) in Mozambique is part of an international survey program (MEASURE DHS) developed by ICF International through a contract with USAID, with the purpose of supporting governments and private institutions in developing countries to carry out national sample surveys in the areas of population and health. The MEASURE DHS Program aims to: </p>
 <p> • Support the formulation of policies and implementation of programs in the areas of population and health; </p>
 <p> • Increase the international population and health data base for monitoring and evaluation; </p>
 <p> • Improve the survey methodology by sampling, and </p>
 <p> • Consolidate, in the survey area, the technical capacity of the executing institution in the country participating in the Program. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[ <p> Ministry of Health (MISAU), <a href="http://www.misau.gov.mz"> www.misau.gov.mz </a>; </p>
 <p> National Statistics Institute (INE), <a href="http://www.misau.gov.mz"> www.misau.gov.mz </a>; </p>
 <p> ICF International (ICFI), <a href="http://www.measuredhs.com"> www.measuredhs.com </a> </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
</mes:GenericMetadata>
        